Register of the Kyril Drenikoff papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- CORRESPONDENCE, 1947-1984 (Boxes 17-44)
  - Doloka-Kaleva, Irene, 1965-1966 (Folder 23: 7)
  - Dotcheff, Ivan
    See Bulgarian National Front
  - Draisma, G. J. H., 1964-1965 (Folder 23: 8)
  - Drenikova-Daskalova, Jeanna, 1957-1966 (Folder 23: 9)
    Correspondence regarding her son pianist Ivan Drenikoff
  - Duchâteau, André, 1961 (Folder 23: 10)
  - Durand-Texte, Gérard, 1967 (Folder 23: 11)
  - Dushnyck, Walter ( The Ukrainian Quarterly), 1973 (Folder 23: 12)
  - Eckhardt, Thorvi (Institut für Osteuropäische Geschichte und Südostforschung der Universität Wien), 1975 (Folder 23: 13)
  - Eldarov, Giorgio, 1963-1972 (Folder 23: 14)
  - Elhadad, René, 1961-1971 (Folder 23: 15)
  - Eller, Carolus, 1969 (Folder 23: 16)
  - Emision Bulgara, Radio Nacional de España, Madrid, 1958-1961 (Folder 23: 17)
  - Enev, Mr., 1983 (Folder 23: 18)
  - Etimov, Dimiter, 1966-1977 (Folder 23: 19)
  - Etinoff, Nedko S., 1959-1982 (Folder 23: 20-21)
    Includes his correspondence and documents as a representative of the Bulgarian National Committee in Lebanon, 1952-1965
  - Etinoff, Nedko S., 1959-1982 (Box-folder 24: 1-3)
  - European Freedom Council (Lombardo, Ivan Matteo), 1964-1973 (Folder 24: 4)
  - Fialon, Olivier, 1981 (Folder 24: 5)
  - Fierens, Jan L., 1962-1972 (Folder 24: 6)
  - Fleury, Serge, 1965-1968 (Folder 24: 7)
  - France. Ambassade (Yugoslavie) (Francfort, P.), 1968 (Folder 24: 8)
  - Franco, Ivan, undated (Folder 24: 9)
  - Frateva-Gianni, Marta-Zena, 1958-1960 (Folder 24: 10)
  - Friedensohn, Rachel (Elly), 1970-1983 (Folder 24: 11)
  - Gabenski, Dora, 1965-1982 (Folder 24: 12)
    See also: SUBJECT FILE/Gabenski, Ivanko
  - Gagov, Joseph M., 1948-1954 (Folder 24: 13-14)
    See also: SUBJECT FILE/Comitato Assistènza Profughi Bulgari and Gagov, Joseph M.
  - Gail, Mildred Ann, 1960-1962 (Box-folder 25: 1)
  - Garan, Sulhi, undated (Folder 25: 2)
  - Gargari, Mirella, 1960-1963 (Folder 25: 3)
  - Garnevski, Andrei
    See: LIGUE BULGARE DES DROITS DE L'HOMME/General
  - Gaucher, Roland, 1966-1967 (Folder 25: 4)
  - Geeraert, Geneviève, 1971 (Folder 25: 5)
  - Genovesi, Luis (Confederación de Organizaciones Anticomunistas República Argentina), 1976 (Folder 25: 6)
  - Georgieff, James D., 1977-1983 (Folder 25: 7)
  - Gerchev, Stephan Petrov, 1976 (Folder 25: 8)
  - Gerganov, Doncho, 1977 (Folder 25: 9)
  - Ghelev, Jivko, 1974-1982 (Folder 25: 10)
  - Gibault, François, 1957-1960 (Folder 25: 11)
  - Giordano, I. (alias Kostoff, Nikola), undated (Folder 25: 12)
  - Gloukhov, Mikhail, 1975-1977 (Folder 25: 13)
  - Gobbi, Franco, 1963-1971 (Folder 25: 14)
  - Goranoff, Kyrill, 1976-1981 (Folder 25: 15)
  - Gorazd, Archimandrite (Folder 25: 16)
    Includes articles on the history of Bulgaria, 1971-1976
  - Gradizione Famiglia Proprietà, 1981 (Folder 25: 17)
  - Gribeauval, Eugène, 1957-1958 (Folder 25: 18)
  - Grigoriv, Georgi, 1970-1982 (Folder 25: 19)
  - Gueneva, Ina, 1957 (Box-folder 26: 1)
  - Gueorgieff, A., 1968 (Folder 26: 2)
  - Guentcheff, Georges
    - 1961-1966 (Folder 26: 3-4)
    - 1967-1982 (Folder 26: 5)
  - Gueorguieff, Gueorgiu, 1957-1981 (Folder 26: 6)
  - Gueorguiev, Petco, 1960-1976 (Folder 26: 7)
  - Guermanoff, Dimitri, 1976 (Box-folder 27: 1)
  - Guisset, Jean-Claude, 1958-1973 (Folder 27: 2-3)
  - Gun, Nerin E., 1981 (Folder 27: 4)
  - Hadji Dimitrov, Peter, 1976-1981 (Folder 27: 5)
  - Hague Academy of International Law, 1957-1969 (Folder 27: 6-7)
    Includes letter to Professor Dupuy relating to Kyril Drenikoff's participation in the Centre d'Etudes et de Recherches auprès de l'Académie de Droit International de La Haye
  - Haïmoff, Adolphe, 1969 (Folder 27: 8)
  - Hefer, Stjepan (Croatian Liberation Movement), 1969-1971 (Folder 27: 9)
  - Héraud, Guy (Institut de Droit et d'Economie Comparés), 1967 (Folder 27: 10)
  - Hilderson, Ady, 1958-1983 (Folder 27: 11-13)
  - Histoire pour tous (Ollive, R.), 1969-1971 (Folder 27: 14)
  - Horizonte Asiatico (Paloma Hayu), 1982-1983 (Folder 27: 15)
  - Hortelano, Antonio, 1959-1972 (Folder 27: 16-17)
  - Hsia Jue-fen, Josephine, 1971-1981 (Box-folder 28: 1)
  - Ichkarov, Metodi, 1976 (Folder 28: 2)
  - Ignatov, J., 1980 (Folder 28: 3)
  - Iliu, Julia F., 1980-1983 (Folder 28: 4)
  - Inkov, Dimiter, 1975 (Folder 28: 5)
  - Institut des Frères des Ecoles Chrétiennes (Frère Antel and others) (Folder 28: 6-7)
    Includes correspondence with the Confédération Mondiale des Anciens Elèves des Frères des Ecoles Chrétiennes, and with Después, 1956-1980
  - Institut des Hautes Etudes Internationales (Paris) (Folder 28: 8)
    Includes correspondence with the Association des Etudes Internationales, 1963-1967
  - Intercercle, 1957-1959 (Folder 28: 9-10)
  - International Advisory Council, undated (Folder 28: 11)
  - International PEN (A World Association of Writers: London Centre for Writers in Exile), 1974 (Folder 28: 12)
  - Ionkoff, Ilia (Institut des Hautes Etudes Internationales, Paris), 1963 (Folder 28: 13)
  - Isakov, A. D., 1977-1983 (Folder 28: 14)
  - Isorni, Jacques, 1968 (Folder 28: 15)
  - Ivanov, Ilian, 1969 (Folder 28: 16)
  - Ivanov, Kiril, 1977-1982 (Folder 28: 17)
  - Ivanov, Mr., 1967 (Folder 28: 18)
  - Ivanov, Tsanko ( Zora), 1976 (Folder 28: 19)
  - Ivanov, Zakhari, 1983 (Folder 28: 20)
  - Ivantchev, Borislav G., 1969-1975 (Folder 28: 21)
  - Jaeger, Corinne, undated (Folder 28: 22)
  - Jaegher, Raymond J. de (Asian Speakers Bureau), 1970 (Folder 28: 23)
  - Jevremolic, Josephine and Milan E., 1965 (Folder 28: 24)
  - Joannis, Léon de, Mrs., 1959 (Folder 28: 25)
  - Jonet, Jacques G. and Martine, 1982 (Box-folder 29: 1)
  - Jongenelen-Hamburger, Ineke, 1958-1981 (Folder 29: 2-3)
  - Jordanova, Radka, 1974 (Folder 29: 4)
  - Jordis von Lohausen, H., 1972 (Folder 29: 5)
  - Karadzhova, Fiorela, 1953-1958 (Folder 29: 6)
  - Karaivanov, Vasilii, 1962-1983 (Folder 29: 7-8)
  - Karamihailov, Kosta, 1969 (Folder 29: 9)
  - Karanescheff, Kosta, 1970-1972 (Folder 29: 10)
  - Karastoianova, Lilet, 1983 (Folder 29: 11)
  - Katzarov, Konstantin, 1968 (Folder 29: 12)
  - Kermekchieva, Zlatka
    - 1956-1971 (Folder 29: 13)
    - 1972-1981 (Folder 29: 14)
    - 1977-1984 (Folder 29: 15)
  - Khaiautov, Georgi, 1968-1972 (Box-folder 30: 1)
  - Kitanoff, Kiril, 1968-1972 (Folder 30: 2)
  - Klark, Reina, 1982 (Folder 30: 3)
  - Klymuk, Halya, 1972-1978 (Folder 30: 4)
  - Kokic, Ivica, 1983 (Folder 30: 5)
  - Konstantinoff, Ivan and Annemarie Haering, 1977-1978 (Folder 30: 6)
  - Koroloff, Larry, 1978 (Folder 30: 7)
  - Kosowski, Radoslaw, 1982 (Folder 30: 8)
  - Kostantina, Pencheva, 1975 (Folder 30: 9)
  - Kostov, Vladimir, 1983 (Folder 30: 10)
  - Kosyk, W. (Union des Ukrainiens de France, L'Est européen), 1967-1981 (Folder 30: 11)
  - Kotarowa, C., 1967 (Folder 30: 12)
  - Kourev, Koncho, 1970 (Folder 30: 13)
  - Kowal, Omelian, undated (Folder 30: 14)
  - Kozhikharov, V., 1981 (Folder 30: 15)
  - Kraus, Milka, 1974 (Folder 30: 16)
  - Krstev, Dimitar, 1976 (Folder 30: 17)
  - Ku, Cheng-kang, 1983 (Folder 30: 18)
  - Kuchar, Roman, 1969 (Folder 30: 19)
  - Kukuzel, Georgi, undated (Folder 30: 20)
  - Kurteff, Kristo, 1981-1982 (Folder 30: 21)
  - Kuzmanov, Strazhik, 1978-1979 (Folder 30: 22)
  - Lançon, M., 1956 (Folder 30: 23)
  - Lawrence, John (Centre for the Study of Religion and Communism), 1972 (Folder 30: 24)
  - Lazarew, George, 1968 (Folder 30: 25)
  - Lefort-Lavauzelle, Silvie, undated (Folder 30: 26)
  - Legrand, Marcel and Michèle, 1967-1980 (Folder 30: 27)
  - Lemmens, N., 1972 (Folder 30: 28)
  - Levordashky, Stefan, 1973 (Folder 30: 29)
  - Ligue Royale Belge d'Athlétisme (Emile Clemmé and Edouard Hermès), 1964 (Folder 30: 30-31)
  - Liutikov, K., 1976-1982 (Folder 30: 32)
  - Loos, Jean, 1956-1970 (Folder 30: 33)
  - Lopatnik, Fernand and Nelly, 1956 (Folder 30: 34)
  - Lopatnik, R., 1958 (Folder 30: 35)
  - Lotthé-Villette, S., 1961-1962 (Folder 30: 36)
  - Loverdo, Costa de, 1966-1967 (Folder 30: 37)
  - Lyautey, Pierre, 1967-1969 (Folder 30: 38)
  - MacGahan American-Bulgarian Foundation, 1979 (Folder 30: 39)
  - Machev, Anton, 1982 (Folder 30: 40)
  - Magnino, Leo, 1963-1973 (Folder 30: 41)
  - Maier, Levi, 1975 (Folder 30: 42)
  - Maineri, Lenore, 1962-1967 (Folder 30: 43)
  - Maison de Victor Hugo (Martine Ecalle), 1968 (Folder 30: 44)
  - Maître, Jean and Antoinette, 1960-1978 (Folder 30: 45)
  - Mamarcheva, Giovanna, 1964-1966 (Folder 30: 46)
  - Manceau, Marie-Thérèse, 1959 (Folder 30: 47)
  - Marès, Roger and Catherine, 1961-1965 (Folder 30: 48)
  - Margarita, Queen of Bulgaria, 1964-1973 (Folder 30: 49)
  - Marie de Sainte Anne, Soeur, 1959 (Box-folder 31: 1)
  - Marinof, Bogomil, 1967-1972 (Folder 31: 2)
  - Marinov, Stefan, 1979-1983 (Folder 31: 3)
  - Mariotte, Pierre, 1956-1957 (Folder 31: 4)
  - Markov, N., 1964 (Folder 31: 5)
  - Marolleau, Georges (Oeuvre d'Orient), 1957-1971 (Folder 31: 6)
  - Martchevski, Dimitre M., 1958-1965 (Folder 31: 7)
  - Matheeff, Mitko, 1973-1983 (Folder 31: 8)
  - Maximy, René de, 1958-1969 (Folder 31: 9)
  - Mazon, André, 1966-1967 (Folder 31: 10)
    Includes correspondence with daughter Jacqueline
  - Mazzocchi, Anna, 1963-1964 (Folder 31: 11)
  - Mei, Chang-ling (China Television Company), 1981 (Folder 31: 12)
  - Mikhailov, Ivan, 1968-1980 (Folder 31: 13)
  - Milkov, Nikolaï, 1966-1977 (Folder 31: 14)
  - Mills, Beaudoin (E. R. Lloyd and Company), 1960-1961 (Folder 31: 15)
  - Miltschewa, Mila, 1973-1983 (Folder 31: 16-17)
  - Minko, Marinoff, 1966 (Folder 31: 18)
  - Miranda, Pacita M., 1971-1983 (Folder 31: 19)
  - Mishev, Altsek, 1978 (Folder 32: 1)
  - Monovsky, Mr., 1982 (Folder 32: 2)
  - Monsch, Charles, 1959-1973 (Folder 32: 3)
  - Montdor, Viviana and Jorge, 1961-1981 (Folder 32: 4)
  - Morley, Joseph and Erna, 1965-1982 (Folder 32: 5)
  - Mosquera, Maria Eulalia, 1959-1982 (Folder 32: 6)
  - Moura, Laércio Dias de, 1959-1973 (Folder 32: 7)
  - Mumenthaler, Adrienne, 1977-1981
    See Association of Bulgarian Political Emigrés in Switzerland
  - Musée de la Légion d'Honneur (Ducourtial, C.), 1967 (Folder 32: 8)
  - Musée Victor Hugo, 1968 (Folder 32: 9)
  - Mussault family, 1956-1959 (Folder 32: 10)
  - Naslednikov, Boris, 1972 (Folder 32: 11)
  - Nasteva, Maria, 1957-1958 (Folder 32: 12)
  - La nation européenne, 1968 (Folder 32: 13)
  - Nebollieff, Michael, 1962-1967 (Folder 32: 14)
  - New Hungarian Quarterly, 1977 (Folder 32: 15)
  - Nicolas, Colette, 1959-1983 (Folder 32: 16)
  - Nicolov, Asen, 1970-1980 (Folder 32: 17)
  - Nikolaeva, Rada, 1980 (Folder 32: 18)
  - Nizamoff, Christo N., undated (Folder 32: 19)
  - Noeff, Georgi, 1970-1981 (Folder 32: 20)
  - Noël, Gérard M. (Europex), 1957-1963 (Folder 32: 21)
  - Noikov, Stephan, 1961 (Folder 32: 22)
  - Norberg, May-Britt, 1958-1972 (Box-folder 33: 1-2)
  - Noronha da Costa, Marcus Soares de Albergaria de, 1965-1968 (Folder 33: 3)
    Includes correspondence with Eduardo Nuñes regarding the film on Boris III, Czar of Bulgaria
  - Nurigiani, Giorgio, 1962-1965 (Folder 33: 4)
  - Onfroy, M., 1968 (Folder 33: 5)
  - Oostpriesterhulp vzwd, 1963 (Folder 33: 6)
  - Oren, Nisan, 1982 (Folder 33: 7)
  - Organisation Mondiale de la Presse Périodique
    See Association des Journalistes Périodiques Belges et Etrangers
  - Osogovski, Iakim, undated (Folder 33: 8)
  - Oster, Achim, 1969-1983 (Folder 33: 9)
  - Oswald-Léon, Frère, 1956 (Folder 33: 10)
  - Oundjieff, Christo M. (Bulgarian Socialist Labor Federation), 1958-1981 (Folder 33: 11-12)
  - Pace, Dominique D. di, 1961-1964 (Folder 33: 13)
  - Pacheff, Jordan, 1957-1958 (Folder 33: 14)
  - Palmer, Mara, 1964 (Folder 33: 15)
  - Panayotof, Panayot and Dora, 1970-1981 (Folder 33: 16)
  - Panev, S., 1978 (Folder 33: 17)
  - Panitza, Dimi, 1965-1969 (Folder 33: 18)
  - Papazoff, Georges, 1966-1972 (Folder 33: 19)
  - Papp, Victor A. (Voice of America), 1979 (Folder 33: 20)
  - Paprikoff, George I. (Box 34)
    - 1961-1983 (Folder 34: 1-2)
    - 1982-1983 (Folder 34: 3)
  - Passos, J. Alfonso de Moraes, 1973 (Folder 34: 4)
  - Pasternak, Marika and Ivan, 1975-1981 (Folder 34: 5)
  - Pavlova, Penka, 1980-1982 (Folder 34: 6)
  - Pcinski, Prohor, 1969-1982 (Folder 34: 7)
  - Péchaudra, Françoise and J.-M., 1957 (Folder 34: 8)
  - Peev, Krazimir, 1979-1981 (Folder 34: 9)
  - Peev and Popov, 1983 (Folder 34: 10)
  - Peichinoff, Augustin, 1966-1968 (Folder 34: 11)
  - Peissel, Jean-Claude, 1959-1966 (Folder 34: 12)
  - Peissel, Michel and Marie-Claire, undated (Folder 34: 13)
  - Peitchev, Velitchko P., 1978-1982 (Box-folder 35: 1)
  - Penev, Loudvig P., 1967-1968 (Folder 35: 2)
  - Penew, Doichin, 1977-1983 (Folder 35: 3)
  - Persévérance-Victor, Frère, 1956-1962 (Folder 35: 4)
  - Pervanov, Veselin, 1975-1982 (Folder 35: 5)
  - Petkoff, Stefan, 1968-1969 (Folder 35: 6)
  - Petroff, Georgi, 1966-1982 (Folder 35: 7)
  - Petroff, Peter, 1979 (Folder 35: 8)
  - Petrov, Lüben, 1976-1978 (Folder 35: 9)
  - Peyev, Jordan V., 1963-1964 (Folder 35: 10)
  - Pierre-Marie, Frère, 1958-1964 (Folder 35: 11)
  - Pierson, Paulette and Paul-Louis, undated (Folder 35: 12)
  - Pisanelli, Federica, 1980-1981 (Folder 35: 13)
  - Plackov, Vincentius M., 1962-1967 (Folder 35: 14)
  - Plumier, Guy, 1971-1975 (Folder 35: 15)
  - Pokorny, Ctibor Edmund, 1967-1971 (Folder 35: 16)
  - Polycarpe, Frère, 1956-1965 (Folder 35: 17)
  - Pondev, N., 1974-1981 (Folder 35: 18)
  - Poorter, Isabelle de, 1981-1982 (Folder 35: 19-22)
  - Popoff, Christo M., 1965-1974 (Box-folder 36: 1)
  - Popoff, Emil, 1956-1976 (Folder 36: 2)
  - Popoff, Nelly, 1978-1982 (Folder 36: 3)
  - Popov, Kharalan, 1983 (Folder 36: 4)
  - Popov, Ladin, 1969-1976 (Folder 36: 5)
  - Popov, Pastor, 1983 (Folder 36: 6)
  - Popov, Stefan, 1982 (Folder 36: 7)
  - Popov, Vida A., 1978-1980 (Folder 36: 8)
  - Possony, Stefan T. and Regina, 1973-1977 (Folder 36: 9)
  - Postorino-Gürowa, Penka, 1983 (Folder 36: 10)
  - Pourquoi pas?, undated (Folder 36: 11)
  - Preslavski, Luka, 1965 (Folder 36: 12)
  - Prodanov, Dragomir
    - 1963-1974 (Folder 36: 13)
    - 1963-1971 (Folder 36: 14)
    - 1969-1971 (Box-folder 37: 1)
  - Pšeničnik, Srecko F., 1983 (Folder 37: 2)
  - Pundev, Marin, 1968-1969 (Folder 37: 3)
  - Radio Free Europe, 1962-1965 (Folder 37: 4)
  - Radio Vaticana, 1968 (Folder 37: 5)
  - Radkova, Ivanka, 1974-1977 (Folder 37: 6)
  - Raichev, Jordan, 1975-1980 (Folder 37: 7)
  - Raikin, Spas T., 1976-1983 (Folder 37: 8)
  - Ranchev, Ivan, 1968-1977 (Folder 37: 9)
  - Rémy, Jean (Compagnie du Cambodge), 1958 (Folder 37: 10)
  - Rencontres (J. Thomas), 1957 (Folder 37: 11)
  - Rigoni, Ernest (Comité Hongrois de Libération Nationale), 1969-1973 (Folder 37: 12)
  - Rindoff, Konstantin, 1964-1965 (Folder 37: 13)
  - Rivista Italia, 1983 (Folder 37: 14)
  - Robev, Ivan G., 1963-1968 (Folder 37: 15)
  - Rocca, Anna, 1965-1967 (Folder 37: 16-17)
  - Rodier, Elisabeth (Box-folder 38: 1)
    Includes correspondence with the Carmel of Sofia, Bulgaria, 1957-1963
  - Rodriguez, Maria, 1959-1980 (Folder 38: 2)
  - Rogel, Pierre and Micheline (Slama), 1959-1965 (Folder 38: 3)
  - Rombouts, Georges-A., 1980-1982 (Folder 38: 4)
  - Rotary International, 1960 (Folder 38: 5)
  - Russewa, Milka, 1968 (Folder 38: 6)
  - Ruty, Paul and Milèna, 1958-1970 (Folder 38: 7)
  - Saccà, Cicita, 1977-1983 (Folder 38: 8)
  - Saint Gille, Nicole, 1959 (Folder 38: 9)
  - Salleh, Nooriah, 1981-1983 (Folder 38: 10)
  - Sarafov, Nicolai, 1981 (Folder 38: 11)
  - Savova, Elena, undated (Folder 38: 12)
  - Schekoff, Todor, 1962-1981 (Folder 38: 13)
  - Schimph, Marianne, 1979-1980 (Folder 38: 14)
  - Schischkoff, Georgi, 1977-1981 (Folder 38: 15)
  - Schlakh Peremohy (Anathole Bedrij), 1972 (Folder 38: 16)
  - Schoen, Jean-Paul, 1956-1964 (Folder 38: 17)
  - Schoffer, Karol, undated (Folder 38: 18)
  - Scott, Ludwig Arthur, 1982 (Folder 38: 19)
  - Semerdjieff, Peter, 1977-1982 (Folder 38: 20)
  - Senghor, Henri Arphang, 1964-1980 (Folder 38: 21)
  - Sergheraert, Gaston (Association pour les Etudes et Recherches Historiques), 1960-1974 (Folder 38: 22-23)
  - Serguieff, Gueorgui, 1958-1963 (Box-folder 39: 1)
  - Services Américains d'Information et de Relations Culturelles, 1968 (Folder 39: 2)
  - Sévault family, 1955-1964 (Folder 39: 3)
  - Shishkov, Peter, 1958 (Folder 39: 4)
  - Shishkov, Stefan, 1966-1968 (Folder 39: 5)
  - Shlendern-Staikova, Natska, 1977 (Folder 39: 6)
  - Shrestha, N. D., 1983 (Folder 39: 7)
  - Shumanov, Iskar, 1973 (Folder 39: 8)
  - Siderov, K., 1966 (Folder 39: 9)
  - Siklunoff, Mr., undated (Folder 39: 10)
  - Simeon II, King of Bulgaria, 1961-1983 (Folder 39: 11-19)
    Includes related material
  - Simeonov, Peter, 1970-1981 (Folder 39: 20)
  - Simov, Vasko, 1958 (Folder 39: 21)
  - Sipkov, Ivan (United States. Library of Congress), 1968-1975 (Box-folder 40: 1)
  - Sirakoff, 1968 (Folder 40: 2)
  - Skarlatti, Alexander, 1978-1979 (Folder 40: 3)
  - Skerlev, Stratiia, 1971-1974 (Folder 40: 4)
  - Slavenov, B., 1978 (Folder 40: 5)
    Includes list of Bulgarians in Trieste who donated money for Easter
  - Société Macédonienne "Todor Alexandroff,", 1970-1980 (Folder 40: 6)
  - Sofoklieva, Mrs., 1983 (Folder 40: 7)
  - Sofranov, Ivan, 1962-1980 (Folder 40: 8)
  - Souza Neto, Alipio Henrique de, 1965-1969 (Folder 40: 9)
  - Spina, Monseigneur, 1962 (Folder 40: 10)
  - Stanchova, Elena, 1964-1973 (Folder 40: 11)
  - Stancioff, Feodora, 1968-1969 (Folder 40: 12)
  - Stantchev, Mihaïl, 1973-1976 (Folder 40: 13)
  - Stateff, Dimko and Anna, 1967-1977 (Folder 40: 14)
  - Statkov, Boriana, 1957-1976 (Folder 40: 15)
  - Statkov, D., 1979-1982 (Folder 40: 16)
  - Stawrowsky, Alexis, 1964-1966 (Folder 40: 17)
  - Stefanov, Ilia, 1978-1981 (Folder 40: 18)
  - Stelson, Stelios M., 1976 (Folder 40: 19)
  - Stewart-Smith, Geoffrey, 1971-1972 (Folder 40: 20)
  - Stoeff, Dimo, 1980-1982 (Folder 40: 21)
  - Storia illustrata, 1970 (Folder 40: 22)
    Correspondence regarding Boris III, Czar of Bulgaria
  - Stoyanov, Stoian, 1968 (Folder 40: 23)
  - Stoykov family, 1957-1985 (Folder 40: 24)
  - Surbiguet, Marcel and Brigitte, 1964-1982 (Folder 40: 25)
  - Suzko, Sonia, 1970-1972 (Folder 40: 26)
  - Tabakov, George A., 1968-1978 (Folder 40: 27)
  - Tabakov, Stefan, 1971-1979 (Folder 40: 28)
  - Tamamdjïéva, Julia, 1977 (Folder 40: 29)
  - Tarnovalisky, Iosif, 1961-1968 (Folder 40: 30)
  - Tcharaktchiev, Simeon, 1975 (Box-folder 41: 1)
  - Tejas, Juan
    See Emision Bulgara
  - Tenev, Getcho, 1976 (Folder 41: 2)
  - Terziisky, M. I., 1981 (Folder 41: 3)
  - Testa, Cardinal, 1962-1967 (Folder 41: 4)
  - Ti-Wiss, Mr., 1960-1962 (Folder 41: 5)
  - Tisserant, Eugène, 1961-1970 (Folder 41: 6)
  - Todorov, Kosta, 1968-1982 (Folder 41: 7)
  - Tontscheff, Kanio and Todor, 1958-1968 (Folder 41: 8-9)
  - Toschkoff, Nicolai and Bistra, 1966 (Folder 41: 10)
  - Trantcheva, Demi, 1964-1965 (Folder 41: 11)
  - Trapp, Martin van Kley, 1958-1968 (Folder 41: 12-13)
  - Trepkoff, Tsone, 1967-1973 (Folder 41: 14)
  - Troisi, Alfredo and Ornella, 1967-1983 (Folder 41: 15)
  - Troubnikoff, Andrei, 1967-1970 (Box-folder 42: 1)
  - Tschekounoff, S., 1967 (Folder 42: 2)
  - Tzokov, Manol, 1980 (Folder 42: 3)
  - Tzolov family, 1947-1961 (Folder 42: 4)
  - Ungerer, Sava, 1969-1975 (Folder 42: 5)
  - United Bible Societies, 1969 (Folder 42: 6)
  - Uwechue, Raph C. (Centre Historique Biafrais), 1968 (Folder 42: 7)
  - Vankerkhoven, Paul (European Parliament), undated (Folder 42: 8)
  - Vankov, Ilia, 1981-1983 (Folder 42: 9)
  - Vanuxem, Paul, undated (Folder 42: 10)
  - Vassileff, Boris H., 1960-1973 (Folder 42: 11)
  - Vassileff, Vassil, 1956-1960 (Folder 42: 12)
  - Vazov, D., 1974-1976 (Folder 42: 13)
  - Veillet-Lavallée family, undated (Folder 42: 14)
  - Velayos, Margarita and Ramón, 1958-1969 (Folder 42: 15)
  - Velazquez-Muñoz, Gabriel, 1960-1965 (Folder 42: 16)
  - Velizarov, Bogdan
    See SUBJECT FILE/Comitato Assistènza Profughi Bulgari
  - Velkov, James D., 1976-1977 (Folder 42: 17)
  - Veltchev, Georgi Georgiev, 1971 (Folder 42: 18)
  - Verga family, 1958-1979 (Folder 42: 19-20)
  - Verga family, 1958-1979 (Box-folder 43: 1)
  - Viellard, Bruno, 1963 (Folder 43: 2)
  - Vulchev, Antim, 1982 (Folder 43: 3)
  - Waltscheff, Dimitre, 1967-1981 (Folder 43: 4-5)
  - Weltscheff, Vladimir, 1968-1983 (Folder 43: 6)
  - Witochynsky, Laryssa, 1970-1977 (Folder 43: 7)
    Includes correspondence with husband Jean-François Drouard
  - Wolf, Ernesto and Liuba (Bojadjieva), 1966-1967 (Folder 43: 8)
  - Woo, Jae-Seung, 1983 (Folder 43: 9)
  - Wouytch, Nicolas de (Chancellerie de S.A.I. le Grand Duc Wladimir de Russie), 1968-1969 (Folder 43: 10)
    Includes a proclamation by the Grand Duc Wladimir of Russia relating to the 1968 Soviet invasion of Czechoslovakia
  - Wytenus, Lauraine, 1981 (Folder 43: 11)
  - Yoo, Hak-seong, undated (Folder 43: 12)
  - Yturriaga Barberan, Jose Antonio de, 1967 (Folder 43: 13)
  - Yu, Melissa (National Taiwan University), 1981 (Folder 43: 14)
  - Zagorsky, Dragomir, 1975-1982 (Folder 43: 15)
  - Zagorsky, Iosif, 1978-1983 (Folder 43: 16)
  - Zahrai, E., 1969 (Folder 43: 17)
  - Zaimova, Zhenia, 1974-1983 (Folder 43: 18)
  - Zannito, Ketty, 1969-1978 (Folder 43: 19)
  - Zaphyrof, Lubomir, 1966-1976 (Folder 43: 20)
  - Zevaco, Claude, 1957-1976 (Folder 43: 21)
  - Zhivkov, Professor, 1971-1982 (Folder 43: 22)
  - Zitoun, Raymond and Renée, 1959-1960 (Box-folder 44: 1)
  - Zlatkoff, Lazar, 1977-1979 (Folder 44: 2)
  - Zotchew, Theodor, 1976 (Folder 44: 3)
  - Zourabichvili, Lévan (Centre National de Politique Géorgienne à l'Etranger), 1968-1974 (Folder 44: 4)
  - Zourabichvili, Salomé, 1978 (Folder 44: 5)
  - Zupan, Jean, 1957-1964 (Folder 44: 6)
  - Miscellany (Folder 44: 7)
- SPEECHES AND WRITINGS, 1958-1983 (Boxes 44-52)
  Articles, books, broadcasts, letters to the editor, literary criticism, reviews, speeches, and academic theses, relating mostly to Bulgarian history, politics, and culture, and to anti-communist movements, arranged chronologically by title. Quite a number of writings were published under pseudonyms, such as D. B., D. D., K. G. D., D. G., D. K. G., D. L. G., G. G., D. V., Strachimir Belphegoroff, G. Bertram, Ieromonakh Danail, Konstantin Dragashov, Gavrets, Gavriil Gorianin, Dr. Gorski, K. D. Gueorguief, Serafim Ionov, Dimiter Iskrenov, S. Kirov, Kolezhanin, G. or Georgi or Gore Lazov, Iskren Ognianov, Pantelei Petnik, G. L. Starozemets, C. D. de Velboudj, and Iurdan Zambakov. See also: SUBJECT FILE/ Kiukov, Luben.
  - "Ami Bouillet,", undated (Folder 44: 8)
    Typescript copy
  - "André Mazon,", undated (Folder 44: 9)
  - "Angel Kunchev," Svoboda, undated (Folder 44: 10)
  - "Antim," Svoboda, undated (Folder 44: 11)
  - "Apogei na debeloochieto," Makedonska tribuna, undated (Folder 44: 12)
  - "A propos d'une légende,", undated (Folder 44: 13)
  - "L'Archevêque Petar Partchevitch,", undated (Folder 44: 14)
  - Article on Soviet-Bulgarian relations, undated (Folder 44: 15)
  - "Asen Peikov,", undated (Folder 44: 16)
  - "Baba Tonka Obretenova" (under the pseudonym of D. D.), Svoboda, undated (Folder 44: 17)
  - "The Balkans One of the World Crisis Areas,", undated (Folder 44: 18)
  - "Belezhiti Bulgaria: Dimiter Petkov,", undated (Folder 44: 19)
  - "Belezhki verkhu publikuvanit naposledokv utaliianskoto spisanie 'Ozhi' spomeni na Neino Velichestvo Tsaritsa - Maika,", undated (Folder 44: 20)
  - "Bitkata pri Klokotnina," Makedonska tribuna ('Sobitia' column), undated (Folder 44: 21)
  - "Bogoridi,", undated (Folder 44: 22)
  - Broadcast on Radio Free Europe relating to the Levant Fair, Bari, Italy, undated (Folder 44: 23)
  - "Bulgaria,", undated (Folder 44: 24)
  - "Bulgaria v chuzhdata literatura prez 1968 godina," Makedonska tribuna, undated (Folder 44: 25)
  - "Bulgaria y la monarquia,", undated (Folder 44: 26)
  - "Bulgarite,", undated (Folder 44: 27)
  - "Bulgaro-srebskite otnoshenia v navecherieto na rusko-turskata voina 1877/8 g.," Makedonska tribuna, undated (Folder 44: 28)